https://www.laserproto.com/privacy-policy

Laser Prototypes Europe Ltd —  Europes Leading Rapid Prototyping and Manufacturing Bureau
Selective Laser Sintering
Direct Metal Laser Sintering (DMLS)
The Company
Why choose LPE?
Directions
LPE | Rapid Prototyping & Additive Manufacturing > Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
Laser Prototypes (Europe) Ltd understand that your privacy is important to you and that you care about how your personal data is used. We respect and value your privacy and are committed to ensuring that we only collect and use your personal data in ways that are described in this policy and in way that is consistent with our obligations and your rights under law.
This privacy policy sets out how Laser Prototypes (Europe) Ltd uses your personal data: how it is collected, how it is held and how it is processed. It also explains your rights under the law relating to your personal data.
What is Personal Data?
Personal data is defined by the General Data Protection Regulation (EU Regulation 2016/679) (the “GDPR”) as ‘any information relating to an identifiable person who can be directly or indirectly identified in particular by reference to an identifier’.
Personal data is, in simpler terms, any information about you that enables you to be identified.
What personal data do we collect?
We may collect the following information:
• First name, last name, gender, marital status and job title
• Contact information including address (billing and delivery), email address and phone number
• Payment information, including bank account details and payment card details
• Demographic information such as postcode, preferences and industry
• Information about how you use our website and products
• Marketing and communications preferences
• Other information relevant to customer surveys and other feedback provided
Where we need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with goods).
It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us.
How will we use your personal data?
Under the GDPR, we must always have a lawful basis for using personal data. This may be because the data is necessary for our performance of a contract with you, because you have consented to our use of your personal data, or because it is in our legitimate business interests to use it. Your personal data will be used for the following purposes:
We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:
• Providing and managing your account.
• Supplying our products to you. Your personal details are required in order for us to enter into a contract with you.
• Communicating with you. This may include responding to emails or calls from you.
• We may use the information to improve our products and services.
• Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interest and fundamental rights do not override those interests
• Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.
Marketing
We may use your data to form a view on what we think you may want or need, or which of our products and services may be of interest or relevant to you.
You may receive marketing communications from us, which may include contacting you by email, telephone or post, if you have requested information from us or purchased goods or services from us or if you provided us with your details when you, for example, made an enquiry, visited our stand at an exhibition or met with one of our representatives, and you have not opted out of receiving that marketing.
You will not be sent any unlawful marketing or spam. We will always work to fully protect your rights and comply with our obligations under the GDPR and the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003, and you will always have the opportunity to opt-out.
Opting out
You can ask us to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by contacting us at any time or by selecting the unsubscribe option in the emails we send.
Where you opt out of receiving these marketing messages, this will not apply to personal data provided to us as a result of a product/service purchase or supply, product/service experience or other transactions.
Where we are relying upon your consent to process personal data, you can withdraw this at any time by contacting us using the details below.
How long will we keep your personal data?
We will not keep your personal data for any longer than is necessary in light of the reasons for which it was first collected. This means that data will be destroyed or erased from our systems when it no longer required.
Security
We are committed to ensuring that your personal data is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the personal data we collect.
Do we share your information?
There may be times when we are required to share your data with third parties. Your information may be disclosed to some of the following third parties:
• Professional advisers including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers who provide consultancy, banking, legal, insurance and accounting services.
• Subcontractors
• Organisations and businesses who may provide services to us such as debt recovery agencies, back up and server hosting providers, IT and system administration service providers, couriers, credit card processors, client relationship management services, document storage providers and suppliers of other back office functions.
• HM Revenue & Customs, regulators and other authorities.
If any of your personal data is required by a third party, as described above, we will  take steps to ensure that your personal data is handled safely, securely, and in accordance with your rights, our obligations, and the third party’s obligations under the law.
In some limited circumstances, we may be legally required to share certain personal data, which might include yours, if we are involved in legal proceedings or complying with legal obligations, a court order, or the instructions of a government authority.
What are your rights?
Under the GDPR, you have the following rights, which we will always work to uphold:
a) The right to be informed about our collection and use of your personal data. This Privacy Policy should tell you everything you need to know, but you can always contact us to find out more or to ask any questions.
b) The right to access the personal data we hold about you by making a data subject access request.
c) The right to have your personal data corrected if any of your personal data held by us is inaccurate or incomplete.
d) The right to be forgotten, i.e. the right to ask us to delete or otherwise dispose of any of your personal data that we have (where it is not required for legal or regulatory purposes).
e) The right to restrict (i.e. prevent) the processing of your personal data.
f) The right to object to us using your personal data for a particular purpose or purposes.
g) The right to data portability. This means that, if you have provided personal data to us directly, we are using it with your consent or for the performance of a contract, and that data is processed using automated means, you can ask us for a copy of that personal data to re-use with another service or business in many cases.
For more information about our use of your personal data or exercising your rights as outlined above, please contact us using the details provided below.
How Can You Access Your Personal Data?
If you want to know what personal data we have about you, you can ask us for details of that personal data and for a copy of it (where any such personal data is held). This is known as a “subject access request”.
All subject access requests should be made in writing and sent to the email or postal addresses shown below.
There is not normally any charge for a subject access request. If your request is ‘manifestly unfounded or excessive’ (for example, if you make repetitive requests) a fee may be charged to cover our administrative costs in responding.
We will try to respond to your subject access request within one month of receiving it. Normally, we aim to provide a complete response, including a copy of your personal data within that time. In some cases, however, particularly if your request is more complex, more time may be required up to a maximum of three months from the date we receive your request. You will be kept fully informed of our progress.
Complaints
If you have any cause for complaint about our use of your personal data, please contact us below. If you are not happy with our response, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office.
You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues. However, we would really appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the ICO so please contact us in the first instance.
How Do I Contact You?
To contact us about anything to do with your personal data and data protection, including to make a subject access request, please use the following details:
Full name of legal entity: Laser Prototypes (Europe) Ltd
Email address: sales@laserproto.com
Telephone number: 028 9070 6940
Postal Address: 4 Prince Regent Road, Belfast, BT5 6QR
Changes to this Privacy Policy
Laser Prototypes (Europe) Ltd may change may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. This may be necessary, for example, if the law changes, or if we change our business in a way that affects personal data protection. We reserve the right to update or amend this policy. This policy will be available on our website www.laserproto.com
Related Pages
Home
Sitemap
Terms & Conditions
Privacy Policy
Quality Policy
News
Testimonial
“It has allowed us to compete in a market place where product quality and time to market are critical issues”
© 2012 Laser Prototypes Europe Ltd. All Rights Reserved.
Direct Metal Laser Sintering (DMLS)
Why choose LPE?
To provide you with the best user experience, this website uses cookies. More infoNo problem
